我好開心返返嚟屋企度
I cannot express to you
What a joy it is to sing that old hymn
我唔可以表達我頭先剛剛唱嗰首老嘅詩歌嗰種感受
That it is well with my soul
係月我靈係安好嘅
I trust that it is well with your soul this morning
我都相信大家都係安好嘅
I do bring you greetings from over 40 evangelical Chinese churches in Paris
我代表法國華人嘅福音教派教會同大家問安
You know when I visit and I preach in the Chinese churches of Paris
I often get one question
我去探訪或者傳導喺法國教會嘅時候通常都被問到一個問題
Which church do you preach in in Paris?
Sorry, which church do you belong to in Paris?
你喺法國邊個教會度侍奉㗎
I tell them no no
我話聽唔係呀
My church is in Los Angeles, California
我嘅教會喺加州羅省
My home church is at Monterey Park Chinese Baptist Church
我嘅母會就係母導員華人真信會
Thank you MPCBC for being my family's home church
多謝母導員華人真信會
你係我嘅家庭嘅母會
My wife could not be with you, be with us these few days
我師母今日唔可以同大家一齊崇拜
She is in Paris still, serving faithfully I am sure
佢仍然喺法國度忠心咁侍奉
Some of you may know that a few weeks ago we were actually in Korea
或者有啲人知道我哋幾個禮拜之前我哋去咗韓國
Sujong's mom is in hospice so we expect her to go be with Jesus at any time
師母嘅媽媽喺善忠嗰個醫院
我哋會覺得佢會快會返癲家
But she is still in this world but we went back a few weeks ago to say goodbye to her
佢仲喺呢個世上我哋幾個禮拜前返去同佢道別
And we will be back to LA for our furlough in next August
我哋嚟緊呢個八月份我會返返嚟麥羅省
So I am sure you will see more of us for a full school year during that time
我相信喺嗰一年之當中大家會見到我更加多嘅機會
But friends, it has been an amazing four years in Paris
朋友們,我喺法國係精彩嘅四年
The Lord has done some amazing things through us and through your prayers
And through your giving a financial support in our ministry
藉著大家嘅禱告同埋你哋經濟上嘅支持
神係為我哋嘅士工做到好多奇妙嘅事
Our strategy there initially was to get to know the local Chinese churches
我哋嘅策略當初係想去認識當地嘅華人教會
So that we could cast a vision for the Great Commission
And train and lead them out in the streets to share the good news of Jesus
以至我哋可以為大使命投射異象
去訓練佢哋同埋鼓勵佢哋出去去傳福音
There is usually no Sunday that I am not preaching in one of those churches in Paris
通常冇一個星期日我唔會喺某個教會度去講道嘅
But that is a means to an end
It's so that we can work with them to share the good news
咁樣係同大家可以互助一齊去分享神嘅訊息
And so this past summer
喺過去一個暑假
You may remember the Paris Olympics
你哋大家會記得巴黎嘅奧運會
The Lord graciously blessed our efforts and we began to see fruit
神好仁慈咁供應我哋嘅努力
We passed out over 5,038 Gospel materials and Bibles
我哋發出咗5,038個福音嘅傳單或者聖經
Including 1,155 Olympic Gospel pens
包括咗1,155像奧運會嘅福音嘅空針
You can see on the top here the Olympic themed trading pens
你睇到喺個視像上面就係奧運嘅空針
And you notice the colors there
Each color represents some aspect of the Gospel
你會注意到上面有唔同嘅顏色
每個顏色係代表聖經裏面唔同嘅部分
And so we were able to pass out these trading pens
and share the full Gospel message
And we told the people we were working with
that in order to give someone a trading pen
they must hear the full Gospel
我哋藉著呢啲交換呢啲空針
我哋可以傳福音
我哋訓練嗰啲人
當佢派出呢啲空針嘅時候
佢首先要將佢同嗰個人分享福音先
So you see several colors
You see green representing creation
你睇到好多唔同嘅顏色喺個空針上面
綠色係代表創造
You see black representing sin in the fall of man
黑就係代表人嘅墜落
Red is the death of Christ for a sacrifice for our sin
紅色係耶穌基督為我罪喺十字架而死
Blue is the gift that we receive of eternal life
藍色就係代表永生同埋有意義嘅人生
White represents forgiveness of sin and gold
The promise of a meaningful and eternal life in Christ
白色就代表我哋嘅罪得以赦免
金色係代表我哋有永生嘅盼望
We shared these pens
Over 1,219 people in Paris
Mostly Chinese people
我哋分享呢啲空針
分享咗1,219個人
大多數都係華人
And praise God, there were over 112 people
who made professions of faith in Christ
讚美主義嘅112個人
佢願意跟隨耶穌
So MPCBC, your prayers and your support
enabled this work by God's grace
所以慕道員華人浸信會
你嘅禱告,你嘅支持
係成就呢件事嘅
Similarly, we have now made these
You see there, there's the Eiffel Tower
And it is a fridge magnet
And it's the same concept of color concept
of sharing the gospel
我哋而家繼續製造咗呢啲
好似睇到呢個空針一樣
有八角巴黎嘅邪塔同有顏色嘅
係擺喺雪櫃上面嘅,送畀人嘅
So we plan this Christmas Chinese New Year
And next summer, we are leading a team
of second generation French Chinese to Senegal
to share in the French language
the good news of Jesus Christ
我哋希望喺聖誕節、新年
或者復活節
我哋將第二代嘅華人
喺法國生存嘅第二代
去教佢做,用法文嚟講福音
So your fundraising a few weeks ago
helps support us in buying these magnets
記得之前我哋幾個禮拜有籌款
買雪糕,就係製造呢啲雪櫃嘅磁石
So thank you for your support
多謝大家嘅支持
Now my message this morning
我今日早上嘅訊息
is about a very young woman
who was very miserable, depressed and desperate
佢講到一個好年輕嘅女子
佢係好絕望、沮喪、痛苦
But she had faith in the midst of misery
但係喺個痛苦嘅中間,佢有信心
Faith to be a risk taker when it wasn't easy
信心佢做個冒險者
當佢嘅生活唔係好容易嘅時候
And the reality of this woman named Ruth
in our passage, was that her life was not bright
老實講,我哋經文裏面呢個女子
路德,佢人生嘅生命當時係唔係好明亮嘅
It was a tragedy
佢係悲劇嘅
She and her mother-in-law Naomi were miserable
佢同佢嘅奶奶離鵝米係好痛苦嘅
The fact is friends that we live in a fallen world of darkness and despair
老實講,我哋生活喺一個黑暗同埋絕望嘅破碎嘅墮落嘅世界裏面
Maybe you can relate to her story
或者你可以同佢有同感嘅
While the Bible addresses the problem of misery
當聖經有解答苦難嘅問題嘅時候
It doesn't necessarily give us all the answers we want
佢通常唔會畀到我哋所有嘅答案
We usually are looking for a reason
我哋通常喺度尋找緊原因
If God is a good God
Why does He allow me to go through this misery?
如果神係一個好嘅神
點解佢要我經歷呢啲痛苦呢?
The Bible never promises us that we'll live without pain in this world
聖經到從來冇承諾
我哋喺世上我哋會冇痛苦咁生活
But the Bible tells us that tragedy and misery
No matter how difficult it may be in life
但聖經話我聽無論我哋嘅痛苦
我哋嘅經歷任何嘅嘢
失望嘅嘢喺我哋生命之中
Is never the last word
永遠都唔係我哋嘅終結
For followers of Christ
作為基督徒嘅跟隨者
The last word
Listen, the last word is always triumph
我哋嘅終結永遠都係得勝嘅
And it often results in mission
通常都係藉著宣教嘅使命
There are many examples in the New Testament
喺新約聖經度有好多嘅例子
There's a cripple who are down and out
有個殘廢嘅人
They experience Jesus
And their life is suddenly transformed
佢哋好老到
但當佢經歷咗耶穌之後
佢嘅生命就改變啦
Their tragedy becomes triumph
佢哋嘅悲劇就成為得勝
And their misery becomes mission
佢哋嘅痛苦就變成咗使命啦
I think of the adulterous woman at the well
我想起嗰個喺井邊嘅行淫戀
After encountering Jesus
She returns to her hometown in Saikar
佢遇見耶穌之後
佢返返佢嘅家鄉聚家
And she says, "Come, see a man
who told me everything I did
Could this man be the Messiah?"
And the Bible says that they came out of the town
and made their way toward Him
佢話,你喺你門來看
有一個人將我素來所行的一切事
都給我說出來了
莫非這人就是基督嗎?
眾人就出城,往耶穌那裏去
And I believe Jesus seeing them at the distance
Wearing their white robes and coming toward Him
He turns to His disciples and He says,
"Look to the harvest, look, it's ready for white
of the harvest."
當耶穌睇到呢群穿着白色衣服嘅罪家女子
走向佢嘅時候,佢就同佢嘅門徒講
佢話,舉目向田觀看,莊稼熟了
They had heard the woman's testimony
佢哋聽到呢個女人嘅見證
And now they came out to experience the Messiah
而家佢出嚟,佢親身咁經歷彌賽亞
Pain can be productive
痛苦可能有生產力
There is purpose in pain
我哋嘅痛苦係有目的嘅
Suffering can accomplish something
苦難可以成就一啲嘅事
From misery to God's mission
By faith
從苦難,憑著信心去到達咗神嘅使命
So this morning we will see in the Old Testament
Another woman named Naomi
今日我哋喺舊約聖經中睇到嘅一個女人叫蘭娥米
She also experienced misery
But she traveled from her tragedy by way of trust
And found God's grace and triumph
呢個女人佢亦都經歷咗痛苦
但透過佢嘅信心同埋佢嘅尋求
佢喺上帝度搵到得勝
Let's look at our passage
Ruth chapter 1 verses 11 through 18
我哋睇下路德記第一章十一至十八節
But Naomi said to her daughter-in-law
"Return home, my daughters
Why would you come with me?
Am I going to have any more sons?
Who could become your husbands?"
蘭娥米說,我的女兒會去爸
為何要跟從我呢?
我還能生兒子作你們的丈夫嗎?
"Return home, I am too old to have another husband
Even if I thought there was still hope for me
Even if I had a husband tonight
And then gave birth to sons"
我的兒女呀,會去爸
我的年紀老了,不能再有丈夫
就算我還有希望
今夜有丈夫,而且也生了兒子
"Would you wait until they grew up?
Would you remain unmarried for them?
Know, my daughters, it is more bitter for me than for you
Because the Lord's hand has turned against me"
你們豈能等著他們長大呢?
你們能守住自己不嫁人嗎?
我的女兒呀,不要這樣
我比你們更苦
因為耶和華的新手擊打我
"They wept aloud again
And Orpah kissed her mother-in-law goodbye
But Ruth clung to her"
在十四節說到兩個媳婦又放聲大哭
Orpah與婆婆吻別
但是魯德卻緊跟著蘭娥米
"Look," said Naomi
"Your sister-in-law is going back to her people
And to her gods, go back with her
But Ruth replied, 'Don't urge me to leave you
Or to turn back from you
Where you go, I will go
Where you stay, I will stay
Your people will be my people
And your god, my god"
蘭娥米說
"漢啊,你嫂嫂已經回到她的百姓和她的神明那裏去了
你也跟你的嫂嫂回去吧
魯德說,不要勸我離開你
轉去不跟隨你
你往哪裏去,我也往哪裏去
你在哪裏住,我也在哪裏住
你的百姓就是我的百姓
你的神就是我的神"
"And where you die, I will die
And there I will be buried
May the Lord deal with me, be it ever so severely
If even death separates you and me"
And when Naomi realized that Ruth was determined
To go with her, she stopped urging her
"你死在哪裏,我也死在哪裏,葬在哪裏
只有死能使你與我分離
不言怨言和話,重重懲罰我
蘭娥米見,魯德決意要跟自己去
就不再對她說什麼了"
Wow, can you feel this passage this morning?
你有沒有感受到今天這段經文?
Perhaps you know moving and making new friends
and adjusting to a new area
are challenging situations
或者你會知道,搬到一個新地方
去認識新的朋友,去適應這個環境
是可以有挑戰性的
The story of Ruth and Naomi's move
is from Moab, a Gentile city
back to Bethlehem in Israel or in Judah
and also a move that would have been full of misery
蘭娥米從摩訶這個異教的國家
回到白里行的故事
也是充滿著痛苦的
Maybe you remember Ruth's Jewish mother-in-law Naomi
and father-in-law Elimelech had two sons
Milan and Kilian
and they had moved to Moab
during a great famine in Canaan
或者你會記得,路德這個猶太的奶奶
蘭娥米和她的老爺伊利米勒
她有兩個兒子叫做馬倫和基蓮
是從加南,在饑荒的時候
搬到去摸鴨的
While living in Moab, the two Jewish sons
of Naomi married a Gentile
Gentile women, Orpah and Ruth
住在摩訶的期間
蘭娥米的兩個猶太兒子
娶了摩訶艾邦的女子為妻
娶了俄爾巴和路德為妻
Now we're not told the circumstances
but Naomi's husband died
and her two sons also died
Leaving Naomi, Orpah and Ruth as widows
and they would have been in a totally desperate
and a total miserable situation
我們不知道當時的情況
蘭娥米的丈夫過世
然後兩個兒子也去世
留下了蘭娥米、俄爾巴和路德成為寡婦
我們可以想像一下
他們當時是多麼的痛苦
They would have been alone
他們當時是很孤單的
They would have been without their husbands
因為他們沒有了他們的丈夫
Without their sons
沒有了他們的兒子
and basically without a future
in that culture
其實在那種習俗之中是沒有將來的
But the story goes on to say that
Naomi learned that there was no longer a famine
in her homeland of Judah
and so she decided to move back to her homeland
故事繼續就是蘭娥米得知
她的祖國猶大不再有饑荒
所以決定她要搬回她的家鄉
So Naomi must have been preparing to go back
packing her things
and she turned and she saw
Orpah and Ruth following after her
蘭娥米一定在收拾行李
她轉身看到兩個媳婦
俄爾巴和路德在跟隨她
And then in verse 8 we see
she says go back
and each of you to your mother's home
May the Lord show you kindness
as you have shown to your dead husbands
And to me, may the Lord grant
that each of you will find rest
in the home of another husband
在第八節,蘭娥米就跟她的媳婦說
你們各自回娘家去吧
願耶和華待你們
將你們待已故的人和我一樣
願耶和華使你各在自己新的丈夫家中得歸宿
You can't really fault Naomi, can you?
I mean, she's wanting to go back home
where she has family members
and where she's familiar
所以怪責蘭娥米
想回她的家鄉祖國
因為她想離開她的親戚朋友近一點
Maybe some of you have experienced
the loss of a spouse
或者你們中間有些人
可能已經經歷過失去了配偶
It's not easy living alone
一個人生活是不簡單的
But she encouraged her daughter-in-laws
to stay with her own people
and to find a husband to provide for their needs
但是她鼓勵自己兩個媳婦
回到自己的民族那裡
去找到一個新的丈夫來滿足他們的需求
And then we see in verse 14 and 15
at this they wept aloud
and Orpah kissed her mother-in-law goodbye
But Ruth clung to her
Look, said Naomi
Your sister-in-law, she's going back to her people
to her gods, go back with her
在第十四、第十五節
娥米吻別了兩個媳婦
然後開始回家的旅程
經過一場勸告
娥爾巴已經轉身回去了
但是路德就抓住他的婆婆
他緊緊抓住娥米
沒有轉身
娥米就跟他說
你嫂嫂要已經回到她的人民
和她的神明身邊
跟她回去吧
After some persuasion Orpah turned back
but not Ruth
Because Ruth had faith
She had faith in the midst of her difficulty
to be a risk taker
娥米勸了她的媳婦
然後娥爾巴已經決定轉身回家鄉
但是路德還是留下
因為他想做一個冒險的
Naomi said, your sister-in-law is going
你嫂嫂已經離開了
Go with her, go to your own people
and go back to your own gods
你跟著她走
回去你自己的人民當中
回去你們的神那裡吧
And then the classic verse in chapter 16
She confesses her love
and her commitment
and her faith to Naomi
and to her God
在經典的十六節之中
路德是將他對於他婆婆的愛
以及對於他婆婆的神那種忠心
She says, don't urge me to leave you
她說,不要勸我離開你
Or to turn back from you
Where you go, I will go
And where you stay, I will stay
Your people will be my people
And your God will be my God
路德說,不要勸我離開你
轉去不跟隨你
你往哪裏去,我又往哪裏去
你在哪裏住,我又在哪裏住
你的百姓就是我的百姓
你的神就是我的神
在路德這個故事當中
我們可以觀察到
儘管我們的處境
儘管我們的感受
如何我們可以從痛苦中
轉向信心的使命
那種信心是怎樣的呢
第一,導致使命的信心
就是一種選擇
你會不會說
帕斯特埃里亞,這個太簡單了
信心就是選擇
它不是一種感覺
信心是一種選擇
而不是一種感覺
以致導致我們有使命的選擇
路德作出了一個選擇
她會跟隨她以前
從未見過的怪物
我可以想像路德一定是
在南娥米的生命中
看到一些東西
有些是在摩訶婦女身上
看不到的東西
南娥米的信心
在她的神之中
是不同於人們的信心
在摩訶婦女之中
南娥米對上帝的信心
和摩訶那種
異議教的神明
是不一樣的
不是一些有時去教會
有時去聖誕節
去崇拜的信心
而是每一天
信心對在她的神
也是信心影響她的選擇
也是影響她的價值觀
就是信心的行動
在信心中
她相信上帝
可以為她準備的東西
重點就是
非基督徒
時時在關注我們
就像路德
看到南娥米的信心
就像路德看到南娥米的信心
你的朋友
你的家人
他們都在關注你
我發現
他們在關注你
不是當事情發展得好
而是當事情失敗
他們特別關注我們的時候
不是因為我們生命順境的時候
是特別在我們生命逆境的時候
他們在關注你
當你在這裡受苦的時候
他們看到你失業的時候
他們看到你在上課的時候
失敗的
他們想看看
作為基督徒是代表什麼呢
我們經歷的考驗
都成為我們的証證
大家都聽過我講過這個例子
就是我們的信心
好像牙膏一樣
當我們一擠的時候
裡面有的東西就會走出來
給人們看到
他們在觀察著我們
如何反應
但在痛苦的時候
信心是一種選擇
你選擇
相信選擇神的話語
信心不是一個感覺
或者你說
我今天不想去教會
我今天不想上班
他不給我足夠的工資
我為什麼這麼早要去呢
我不想上課
但作為一個成熟的人
就會去
信心是一個選擇
尼奧米選擇信心
選擇回到她的家鄉
但路德
選擇信心
選擇回到一個陌生的國家
她不知道當地的文化
她不知道當地的語言
或者她不懂得當地的語言
我不是很清楚
但她選擇這個冒險
或者和大家
在座比較年長的頂子妹們
或者你年輕的人
作為父母
就好像我們的父母
或者祖父母
他們選擇冒險
而你們這個下一代
你們正在收穫
你們的祖父母
或者你父母
為你們所選擇正確的
你們正在收穫
你們的祖父母
或者你父母
為你們所選擇正確的
你們知道嗎
在苦難之中
你們的信心的選擇
也會影響你們下一代
你們的再下一代
你們正在創造信心的遺產
所以信心是一個選擇
我亦都在這個經文中看到
信心亦都是一個承諾
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
Ruth not only made a choice
to move with her mother-in-law
she also made a commitment
to her and God
我和一對未婚夫妻
只要去市政廳登記
他們可以同居
I guess it's a kind of trial run
They just try it out first
We call it shacking up
when I was growing up
We just shack up
他們試婚
其實在我們年代叫同居
他們就可以享受市政廳的福利
It's like test driving a car
before you see if it's suitable for you
Does it strike your fancy?
好像試駕駛一輛車一樣
看看適不適合你
看看你喜不喜歡
But my friend, I'm here to tell you
shacking up is not a real relationship
但朋友們,我告訴你
同居不是代表真正的關係
Why? 為什麼?
Because there's no real commitment
因為當中沒有真正的承諾
But Pastor Eric, we really do love each other
但你說Pastor Eric
我們真的彼此相愛
Do you really? 是嗎?
So many times we have
such an exclusively romantic
or practical view of love
I fell in love
It's such a great feeling
Pastor Eric
很多時候我們對愛
有一種很獨特的浪漫感覺
我們會說Pastor Eric
我墮入愛河
那種感覺真的太好了
But love is less about a feeling
and more about a commitment
但是愛是少一點的感覺
而是多一點的承諾
Regardless of feelings
or practicalities
regardless of financial feasibility
whether for richer or poorer
we're committed
不考慮感情
或者是考慮經濟可能性
無論是貧窮或者富有
我們都是有承諾的
This is the kind of commitment
that Ruth had for Naomi
and her God
and it didn't depend on how she felt
in the moment
Hebrew chapter 11 verse 1
describes this kind of faith
It says now faith is the assurance
of things hoped for
the convictions
of things not seen
是未見之時的確句
我有一個舊的戲
我想跟大家在這裡提一提
就是《奪寶奇兵》這套戲
如果你記得的話
你都很老了
對不起 我年紀大
沒有道路
你記不記得主角
Indiana Jones
他要隔開一個峽谷
但是他看不到
有任何可以渡過的方法
他突然想起
有一個看不見的路
他閉上眼睛
他就踏入開放空間
他就閉上眼睛
就將他
踏出他的
本空之中
and then
and only then
does the path appear
the step of faith
comes before
the path appears
Friends that is faith
that is commitment
you don't see the path
you don't see the door
that God is opening
but you take a step of faith
because you trust you have a good God
you trust you have
a good God
on one occasion
the disciples were in a boat
in the midst of a great storm
and Jesus was walking
upon the water toward them
Peter
Peter full of zeal
and was moved
said Lord
can I come to you on the water
Jesus said
get out of the boat
Friends true faith
is actually getting out of the boat
if you want to walk on water
if you want to go
from misery and mundane
to God's mission
you have to get out of the boat
Jesus is not in the boat
he is in the water
some of you are very very
comfortable in the boat
but Jesus is not in the boat
and he is looking for people
who will get out of their comfort zone
and get out of their boat
little secret for you
next summer
you'll have an opportunity
to get out of the boat
you don't know it yet
but you will have an opportunity
I've been talking with Pastor Caleb
and you'll have an opportunity
to come to Paris
and join me
outside the boat
you can join us on a short term mission
he said but Pastor Eric
I don't really know how to share my faith
I don't know how to share my testimony
but it doesn't matter
I will train you
I will be with you
and we'll do the great commission together
but you've got to get out of the boat
you are not paying me
to get out of the boat
there is a third
and final
principle that I see
in this passage
this morning
we've seen that faith
that takes us from our misery
to mission is a choice
faith goes beyond the choice
it is a commitment
but biblical faith
listen
biblical faith
always
leads
to God's mission
for Ruth
her faith took her
not only
to a new country
but also to a new life
it took her
not only to a new country
but also to a new mission
it brought her to a new
meaning
and purpose
to her life
if we were to continue to look
at the life of Ruth
in the book of Ruth
we would find that when she got to Judah
it was still not easy
she still had to serve as a slave
and a servant
and get her meals
directly from the field
because of what the harvesters left behind
but I'm here to tell you
that God did provide her food
and she provided for her
a rich
and handsome
and buff husband
and his name was Boaz
Ruth and Boaz were privileged
to be in the generational
line of King David
and
were personal relatives
and progenitors
of Jesus Christ
Matthew chapter 1
verse 5 through 6
is a genealogy of Jesus
summon the father of Boaz
whose mother was Rahab
begot Boaz
the father of Obed
whose mother was Ruth
and Obed the father of Jesse
and Jesse the father
of King David
you see this is the generational
line of Jesus
and Ruth
had her role
in making Jesus
the incarnate Christ
what an honor
what a precious mission
and here's what I'm asking you
friends at MPCBC
I ask you not
to waste your life
I've known many of you for
my goodness
over 30 almost 40 years
do you know that
our life young people
I'm telling you old people
our life will be over
before you know it
unless Jesus comes back
we'll all be in Rose Hill
one day
some of us before others
but please
get out of the boat
you may have
20 more years
you may have 50 more years
got to get out of the boat
do you want
to enjoy
a life of purpose
and being on God's mission
first of course you have to trust
Jesus as your lord and savior
but I encourage you
to be on mission with Jesus
and I've got a secret for you
your salvation
my salvation
it's not about us
our salvation
is about God's glory
and at the end of the day
there are 3 things
that you can do with your life
doesn't matter if you have 5 years left
or 50 years left
you can do 3 things with it
you can waste it
you can be online all the time
you can play online games
you can
you can just exist
or you could spend your life
you could
make millions in the stock market
good for you
that's wonderful
you can enjoy life
you can spend it
you can take vacation a holiday
you can enjoy life
you can take vacation
or you can invest it
the scripture is very clear
do not lay up treasures
on earth
lay up treasures in heaven
invest your life
in that which is eternal
two things are eternal
there are only two things
that aren't going to burn
your cars are going to burn
your houses are going to burn
your clothing will wear out
your degrees on the wall
will disappear
two things are eternal
the word of god
and the souls of men
if you have two years left
five years left
fifty years left
invest in these things
let's pray together
father god we are so thankful
that you have
challenged us this morning
not to just exist
not just to
live a life
in this world
but lord you've given us the opportunity
that we may be going through
struggle right now
we may be like ruth
and boas that felt bitter
and didn't see a way out
in life
but you've shown us
through her example
that we can go
from misery
to meaning
by way of your mission
by faith
father god thank you
for the challenge
thank you for the opportunity
that we can invest our life
in that which is eternal
in jesus name we pray
Amen